<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata>
    <name>Furtherance</name>
    <directory>furtherance</directory>
    <description>[img]https://imgur.com/9RMULvf.png[/img]
A complete overhaul of the old Furtherance MOD originally released in 2022. Coded from the ground up under the experienced eye of a single coder with the power of REPENTOGON, this new release breathes new life into every corner of the original MOD to create a sizeable quality package of content.

[h2]Features:[/h2]
[list]
[*]3 characters and 3 tainted characters
[*]Full completion mark unlocks for all characters
[*]90 items
[*]20 trinkets
[*]20 cards and runes
[/list]

[img]https://imgur.com/SgnitFv.png[/img]
Jacob's first wife
Starts with Heart Renovator, a flowering representation of Leah's love
Red health can overflow into a heart counter. Turn them into broken hearts and mend them with Heart Renovator to feel a little stronger, or leave them broken to get your tears flowing

[img]https://imgur.com/OOclQB2.png[/img]
One of the twelve apostles of Christianity
Starts with Keys to the Kingdom, a gift from the angels to open the gates of heaven
Use it to spare enemies. Bosses take longer to spare. Has special interactions with angels and in devil rooms!

[img]https://imgur.com/VBeVhFO.png[/img]
Moses' sister and the first female Jewish prophetess
Starts with Polydipsisa and Tambourine, overflowing with water and shaking enemies off your tail
Shoot large arcing tears that leave damaging puddles. Puddles that touch have their lifetime extended!
Tambourine inflicts knockback to nearby enemies and briefly creates a gigantic puddle to help increase the lifetime of other puddles

[h2]Mod Compatibility[/h2]
[list]
[*]EID (Full English support. Translators are welcome to help!)
[*]Fiend Folio
[*]Epiphany
[*]The Future
[*]Pog For Good Items
[*]And more!
[/list]

[h2]Links[/h2]
We have a Discord Server where you can talk with the team and other fans of the mod
[url=discord.gg/fy2ACyxDt6]Join here![/url]

We have a Wiki on the Modding of Isaac Wiki...but it's heavily WIP!
Check the wiki [url=https://moddingofisaac.wiki.gg/wiki/User:BenevolusGoat/Furtherance]here[/url] if you wish to check it out anyways
A wiki on Furtherance will also come soon to IsaacGuru

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[img]https://imgur.com/zviAv2l.png[/img]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/benevolusgoat/]Benny[/url]: Coded almost everything

[img]https://imgur.com/GOhI8Jb.png[/img]
Explodingturtle: Commissioned Benny to fix up this mod

[img]https://imgur.com/wQt6ed5.png[/img]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2737123333]The original Furtherance Team[/url]
(Left to right, top to bottom)
[list]
[*]Demi (Spriter)
[*]anchikai (Lead Dev, Coder)
[*]oddivo (Designer)
[*]poody_blue (Spriter)
[*]Shoop (Coder)
[*]BrakeDude (Coder)
[*]Sky (Designer)
[*]PixelPiz (Spriter, Coder)
[/list]

[url=https://steamcommunity.com/id/Warhamm2000]Warhamm[/url]: Commissioned to provide numerous new and refurbished sprites
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198211529504]Ferpe[/url]: Thumbnail artist, and a few other misc sprites
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/profiles/76561198371196314]Muffin Tea[/url]: Most of the new item costume sprites

[h2]Special Thanks[/h2]
[url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3012430463]The Epiphany team[/url]! Many of Furtherance's handy tools and helper code files come from Epiphany

[img]https://imgur.com/WH2LUbP.png[/img]</description>
    <version>1.0</version>
    <visibility>Public</visibility>
    <tag id="Lua"/>
    <tag id="Items"/>
    <tag id="Active Items"/>
    <tag id="Trinkets"/>
    <tag id="Pills"/>
    <tag id="Cards"/>
    <tag id="Pickups"/>
    <tag id="Player Characters"/>
    <tag id="Familiars"/>
    <tag id="Enemies"/>
    <tag id="Challenges"/>
    <tag id="Shaders"/>
    <tag id="Sound Effects"/>
</metadata>
